<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Obligatory on Hsing-Yu Shih</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/tags/obligatory/</link><description>Recent content in Obligatory on Hsing-Yu Shih</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 17:05:31 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hugoshih.com/tags/obligatory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hukou Armored 584 Brigade Combined Arms 2nd Battalion Phase 2 Training Reflection</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/hukou-armored-584-brigade-combined-arms-2nd-battalion-phase-2-training-reflection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2023 17:05:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/hukou-armored-584-brigade-combined-arms-2nd-battalion-phase-2-training-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/jGwuusU.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Hukou Armored 584 Brigade Combined Arms 2nd Battalion Phase 2 Training Reflection" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="hukou-armored-584-brigade-combined-arms-2nd-battalion-phase-2-training-reflection"&gt;Hukou Armored 584 Brigade Combined Arms 2nd Battalion Phase 2 Training Reflection
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time flies very fast. It has been four months since I left 584 Brigade &lt;em&gt;(2022/10/26~2023/01/06)&lt;/em&gt;. As time goes by, memories of the army fade away little by little. It is time to record memories of this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="preface"&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This story probably starts from drawing lots at the tail of boot camp. People interested in boot camp experience can read my previous article. Still remember when drawing lots everyone calculated various drawing techniques. Like analyzing units left in lot cylinder. Touching which direction of lot cylinder easier to get good lot etc. Because this batch are all Taipei soldiers. Relatively good lots like Guandu Area Command, Reserve Command etc. units around Taipei. These units easiest to go home on holiday. Bad ones like Matsu Defense Command, Hualien Defense Command these places very troublesome to go home. And like &lt;em&gt;21 Artillery&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;584 Brigade&lt;/em&gt; are group not up not down. And unfortunately this part of lots are the most. And I just happened to draw &lt;strong&gt;584 Brigade Supply Soldier&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going down to unit everyone inquired various information related to drawn unit from squad leader, battalion commander. And 584 is probably that kind of mediocre. Tank battalion, combat unit might be very tired. Food might be good. Sound like not particularly cool unit. Located in Hsinchu Hukou although very close to freeway. But not very easy to go home either. But thinking still have worse Hualien Defense Command. Psychologically more passable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second day back from boot camp leave. Under mutual farewell of boot camp peers; Carrying heavy Yellow Pu bag and terrible convenience store bread. Sat on bus to 584 Brigade. Actually still one boot camp same bed also drew this unit. Plus same company also had dozen people. This journey not lonely. Bus departed from Taichung Chenggong Ridge at ten something in morning. Three four hours later drove into Hukou camp area. Started my life in 584 Brigade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="about-phase-2-life"&gt;About Phase 2 Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phase 2 life and boot camp are worlds apart. Boot camp had no freedom. While phase 2 had partial freedom. For example: mobile phone. Having mobile phone gave me bit more spiritual solace to survive remaining two and half months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="tortuous-entry"&gt;Tortuous Entry
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When big bus from Chenggong Ridge slowly drove into camp area in Hukou we thought already arrived our new home. Actually this journey just started. When arrived bus stopped at a assembly ground of 542 Brigade camp area. Watching peers of other buses get off one after another. Doubt started in heart isn&amp;rsquo;t already arrived? About waited ten minutes bus started again. Wonderful thing happened. Bus actually slowly drove out of camp area. At this time suddenly remembered: Hukou has several camp areas. We should be going to another camp area right. Sure enough few minutes later we arrived at 584 Brigade camp area located on other side of Hukou. Came into view are old houses and cafeteria similar to Chenggong Ridge. Can&amp;rsquo;t help OS in heart: where are agreed new barracks&amp;hellip; After stopping we were called off bus to gather at cafeteria. And started assigning units. Also simultaneously observing where called people go. Avoided waiting another period of time finally turn to us. After called out originally thought would walk to our barracks. Result we were arranged to get on a medium tactical vehicle. Followed by confusing situation happened again. We actually left camp area again. At this time suddenly remembered seems officer said 584 Brigade also has a camp area in Taoyuan. Heart shocked: no way, we going to Taoyuan!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medium tactical vehicle drove slowly. Slowly passed through alleys of Hukou. About passed 20 minutes. Medium tactical vehicle drove into a place never thought of: &lt;strong&gt;Army Northern Assessment Center&lt;/strong&gt;. When drove into main gate still couldn&amp;rsquo;t help looking at lot in hand. I drew 584 Brigade that&amp;rsquo;s right. Have to say first impression of Northern Assessment Center is good. Here no gray black houses or camouflage bunkers. Instead red appearance building and large piece of neat beautiful lawn. Compared to army camp here more like a school. Really glad assigned here. No need to endure camp barracks broken to no good like Chenggong Ridge anymore. Later explained by officer. Due to historical factor of 584 Brigade. Combined Arms 2nd Battalion we assigned to temporarily reside in Northern Assessment Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://th.bing.com/th/id/OIP.tM-9BhYUNHeOLauZLKaQdgHaFj?pid=ImgDet&amp;w=640&amp;h=480&amp;rs=1" width="60%" alt="Image description" &gt; Appearance of Medium Tactical Vehicle
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="about-584-brigade"&gt;About 584 Brigade
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Army unit of Republic of China guarding Hsinchu County Taiwan. Assigned to Army 6th Corps Command. Armored 584 Brigade team name &amp;ldquo;Dengbu Unit&amp;rdquo;. Predecessor is Army Infantry 284th Division. Before dissolving in Jing-Shi Case this division long term stationed in Kinmen Nanxiong defense area. Therefore also known as &amp;ldquo;Nanxiong Division&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armored 584 Brigade. From name know we are an armored vehicle unit. So besides general military vehicles. Unit also has very many armored vehicles and tanks. Armored vehicle mainly responsible for transporting infantry to combat location. Sometimes also provide small amount firepower support. Tank mainly responsible for outputting firepower. Because armored unit here. Every day can hear sound of tanks circling in camp area. Quite spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://th.bing.com/th/id/R.4f4653c90d412957ac115b26b15d7a28?rik=Dzu0TwJPxsbKBQ&amp;pid=ImgRaw&amp;r=0" width="60%" alt="Image description" &gt; This is armored vehicle
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;584 Brigade has another name. Called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Dengbu&amp;rdquo; Unit&lt;/strong&gt;. Legend during Civil War once won battle at Dengbu Island along coast of China. Later awarded name Dengbu. From here also can see 584 Brigade is unit full of history. During service period happened to encounter team anniversary. By the way visited team history museum. Is very special experience. Also deeper understanding of National Army. 584 Brigade also very solid unit. Before coming to Hukou unit stationed in Kinmen. Located at first line of defense. Requirement for combat power very high. And in 80s of Republic era only transferred back to Taiwan stationed in Hsinchu Hukou due to various reasons. Before coming Hukou was originally military important place. Have several brigades stationed here quite crowded. And 584 Brigade considered new neighbor. Therefore only can disperse parasitic in several camp areas of Hukou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Battalion I am in called &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Combined Arms 2nd Battalion&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. Due to various reasons currently stationed in Army Northern Assessment Center. This place is used for testing combat power. Therefore often see many units lead team come here conduct combat, physical fitness etc. tests. Northern Assessment Center located on Shengli Road Hukou. Most Hukou people should know one side of Shengli Road from north to south all military camps. To arrive here not as easy as Chenggong Ridge. Chenggong Ridge very close to High Speed Rail station. Five minutes drive. Even can arrive by walking. And Hukou camp area distance Hsinchu High Speed Rail station at least twenty minutes drive. Closer station is Hukou Train Station. But speed not as fast as High Speed Rail. After coming out from Hsinchu High Speed Rail station just say to driver want go to first encountered camp area on Shengli Road (but formal name is Hukou 4th Camp Area) fine. Journey will pass section of tortuous climbing. Finally turn onto Shengli Road Hukou. From High Speed Rail station to camp area easier. But from camp area to High Speed Rail station very troublesome. Most time cannot call car. Even called might have to wait twenty thirty minutes. For obligatory service only few holidays want rush back Taipei not very friendly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/df/584r.png" width="30%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dengbu Team Emblem&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="troop-type-and-unit-allocation"&gt;Troop Type and Unit Allocation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our batch threw to 584 Brigade roughly have following troop types: &lt;em&gt;Rifleman, Clerk, Supply Soldier, Driver&lt;/em&gt;. Then what relationship these troop types have with doing things in phase 2? &lt;strong&gt;Answer is completely no relationship&lt;/strong&gt;. Care you drew what soldier. Even if name very handsome 66 rocket soldier arrived phase 2 unit later all are &lt;strong&gt;Rifleman&lt;/strong&gt;. Mainly we in boot camp stage also only received rifle training. So only can operate rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although said all riflemen. But doing things still somewhat different. And mainly related to assigned unit. You will be assigned to what unit irrelevant to drawn troop type. Purely related to company at time of boot camp. I guess they probably just purely arranged according to unit personnel demand. Therefore boot camp same company people arrived 584 Brigade later also big chance will be in same battalion and same company. Like at boot camp my company was &lt;strong&gt;Firepower Company&lt;/strong&gt;. And most people in Firepower Company who drew to 584 Brigade later also assigned to Combined Arms 2nd Battalion &lt;strong&gt;Combat Support Company&lt;/strong&gt;. Only few people assigned to Combined Arms 2nd Battalion Firepower Company next door. Things done in phase 2 largely related to nature of company. In Combined Arms 2nd Battalion there are companies purely providing firepower like: Firepower Company, Combat 1st Company, Combat 2nd Company&amp;hellip; Also have purely support nature Combat Support Company. Combat Support Company responsible for support work during combat. Besides offensive firepower support also provide like food, medical, communication, maintenance related support. In terms of daily life companies purely providing firepower train more. And Combat Support Company miscellaneous things more. Can be assigned to Combat Support Company is lucky. Every time seeing people of other companies move guns ammunition out prepare war everyday evening move back. Will feel better just do miscellaneous things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Combat Support Company support affairs many. Therefore internal divided into several platoons. Each platoon responsible for one business (food, medical, communication, maintenance). And platoon I assigned called &lt;strong&gt;Battalion Headquarters Platoon&lt;/strong&gt;. Mainly assisting battalion officers handle various miscellaneous things. I in period contacted like help officer serve food, clean hygiene, photocopy data, build command post etc. Not considered very heavy difficult work. However because will contact battalion officer first line. Doing things how to make battalion officer happy is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="phase-2-must-bring-things"&gt;Phase 2 Must Bring Things
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Phase 2 suddenly much more can do own things. Life no longer simple like boot camp. Therefore much more demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="consumption"&gt;Consumption
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Small Change&lt;/strong&gt; - Phase 2 will suddenly have many opportunities can use money. You will have lot of time can go to camp store (basically rest time can go. As long as camp store opens). Camp store besides various snacks drinks let you feel beauty of outside world. Also hot food section. If don&amp;rsquo;t want eat lunch provided by kitchen can also try fried noodles, braised pork rice, fried chicken leg of camp store. These mostly pay cash. Bring one two hundred yuan few days will spend. In addition some squad leaders very nice to voluntary service. Also willing help obligatory service take out outside food. You think yesterday eat KFC today eat Pizza hut. This is thing completely unimaginable when new recruit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;EasyCard with Automatic Reload&lt;/strong&gt; - That kind integrated EasyCard is simply Doraemon&amp;rsquo;s magic tool. Besides partial vending machines can use. Camp store, or further walk to OK convenience store in 542 Brigade camp area can use EasyCard. Buy whatever want buy. Very convenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="food"&gt;Food
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Instant Noodles&lt;/strong&gt; - When your action range expand to whole Hukou camp area. Almost no daily necessities cannot buy. Instant noodles same logic. However if have specific flavor want eat still can bring in from outside beforehand stock. Late night making cup noodle in dormitory really evil. Occasionally take instant noodle honor officer build relationship also can exchange little bit relax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Snacks&lt;/strong&gt; - Same logic. Most snacks also can buy. Most time you will lazy walk so far go buy things. So bring in early stock more convenient. Also can sell to neighbor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Drinks&lt;/strong&gt; - Drink choices in camp area less. And still have many that kind strange drinks completely never seen outside. Relatively that kind tetra pak drink choice also less. Only OK has small amount. If want drink specific models also suggest bring back when returning from holiday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="clothing"&gt;Clothing
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Jacket&lt;/strong&gt; - Usually training time cannot wear own jacket. Except morning assembly and exercise time. My phase 2 time is November to January. This period Hsinchu wind big and cold. Really need have a warm jacket. New recruit issued white green jacket really sucks. If entering camp in winter must bring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Warm Clothing&lt;/strong&gt; - Enter camp in winter must bring. Especially weather particularly cold few days night sleeping really will be cold protect. So some thick long pants or thermal underwear very necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sneakers&lt;/strong&gt; - Phase 2 exercise time also can wear own sneakers. So if feel issued shoes hard to wear or worn out. Then can also bring own sneakers in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Sport Shorts&lt;/strong&gt; - Boot camp sport shorts only issued one. Because wear shorts every day. So usually wash once a week very disgusting. Phase 2 exercise time can wear own shorts. Usually can prevent one pants wear several days situation. Own pants also more comfortable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Laundry Powder&lt;/strong&gt; - Boot camp wash clothes is clothes to wash use laundry bag concentrate find outside vendor unify send wash. Phase 2 due to such demand not big. Default is directly use washing machine on camp wash self. Then of course laundry powder part have to bring self. However our phase 2 peer obligatory service more. Discussed with officer want unify send wash. So later officer also help us find vendor handle. No need self grab washing machine someone help wash good really convenient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="tableware"&gt;Tableware
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bowl&lt;/strong&gt; - Phase 2 finish restaurant tableware will unify recycle keep. Phase 2 bowls plates etc. self keep. If feel meal tray provided by camp hard use, hard wash. Can also bring big bowl self. Loading dish loading rice will convenient much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="bedding"&gt;Bedding
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Quilt&lt;/strong&gt; - Folding quilt definitely most painful thing when soldier wake up. Boot camp requirement for quilt high strive for edges and corners. Spend twenty thirty minutes folding quilt not exaggeration. Phase 2 no longer will have officer want you must spread quilt. Or you basically can directly cover own quilt. Daytime put back quilt completely never spread. Own quilt stuff back into internal affairs cabinet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Many Power Banks&lt;/strong&gt; - Our company rule is night can use extension cord connect phone charger charge. But daytime only use power bank charge. Never underestimate phone usage. Since too boring in camp area. One day phone usage time is ten hours start. Naturally power bank also carry along. Usually have two power banks can ensure everyday at least one power bank has electricity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Power Adapter&lt;/strong&gt; - Want charge phone or power bank then of course need that kind 110v to type-c adapter. Best bring few more backup avoid missing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Wired Earphone&lt;/strong&gt; - In army principle cannot bring bluetooth earphone. Only can bring wired earphone. Phase 2 earphone also use anytime. Besides talk phone with family girlfriend use. Bored want low profile watch drama, watch youtube also very useful. Just wear earphone in training time be sure low profile. Seen by officer still will angry. Also earphone also suggest &lt;em&gt;bring few more&lt;/em&gt;. Since usage chance many. Broken chance also many. I in camp area had accidentally pull break one. Again no prepare backup. Cause that week want talk phone or watch video become very troublesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="medicine"&gt;Medicine
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Cold Medicine&lt;/strong&gt; - Once arrive phase 2 suddenly become easily catch cold. Possibly chance stay in closed space with neighbor increase. When catch cold although Northern Assessment Center has infirmary. But medical officer quite useless. Besides prescribe some comprehensive cold medicine only will transfer. So if symptom not too serious then eat cold medicine self fine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Mosquito Repellent&lt;/strong&gt; - Phase 2 officer also won&amp;rsquo;t require you must hang mosquito net. Although night sleep window will close. But inevitably have mosquito sneak in and drive not away. At this time only can rely on mosquito repellent or some anti-itch medicine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="daily-schedule"&gt;Daily Schedule
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared to boot camp every link planned well. Phase 2 life relatively much flexible. Except assembly time very fixed. Daily assembly time, rest time, eating time not that fixed. Mostly will different according to daily training, business content. Compared boot camp that kind every minute every second very critical life. Phase 2 really pressure small much. Daily schedule roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;06:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Wake Up&lt;/strong&gt; - Our phase 2 time is according to winter time. Wake up time compare summer time 05:30 can have 30 minutes more sleep time. Phase 2 unlike boot camp will wake up earlier 30 minutes. Anyway requirement for quilt not high. Morning about spend ten minutes can settle quilt and wash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;06:20&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - After wash can slowly move to assembly ground assemble. This assembly wear usual exercise uniform fine. Unlike boot camp only obligatory service assemble. Yesterday duty stay obligatory service will also assemble. Watching obligatory service also look sleepy very interesting. This assembly is duty squad leader roughly look person missing or not. Not missing squad leader mood good bring everyone do some exercise. But most time directly release everyone go down eat breakfast. Suggest steal bowl chopsticks stuff into pocket bring down when assemble. So no need run back dormitory one more trip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;06:00 ~ 06:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Eat Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt; - Compared to boot camp too many people restaurant cannot sit. Phase 2 after breakfast time restaurant super empty. Voluntary service have outside eating sleeping rarely come in eat breakfast. We obligatory service sometimes also want go back steal sleep. Also not necessarily want eat. 584 Brigade breakfast beginning come very delicious. Later don&amp;rsquo;t know why worse and worse. Only left steamed bun, few small dishes, porridge, and sweet soup. Mediocre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;07:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - This assembly want full gear (helmet, S-belt). Then will conduct singing counting numbers. That is first come few singing counting numbers. Then lead sing military song like &amp;ldquo;Army in Charge&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;07:30 ~ 11:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Training Class&lt;/strong&gt; - See what schedule of day is. Since our unit experiencing pre-base training. Therefore quite a lot training content targeting down base like CPR, combat injury rescue, night vision goggles etc. Mainly still train voluntary service. Obligatory service beside fill number. No class then maintain gun in Zhongshan room or slide phone be redundant. Occasionally called out help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;11:00 ~ 12:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Lunch&lt;/strong&gt; - Different from boot camp. Lunch before no longer assemble. Just after class respective return dormitory unload gear take bowl chopsticks then self go restaurant eat. Finish eat self return rest. Lunch compared boot camp quite good. Usually have two to three main dishes. Then dish amount also very sufficient. Won&amp;rsquo;t have dish not enough situation in boot camp. In addition one sweet one salty soup can choose. Sometimes have add dish. Can eat something different like hot pot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;12:00 ~ 13:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Nap&lt;/strong&gt; - Nap just return dormitory rest sleep. Don&amp;rsquo;t mess do whatever want do. No one will care you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;13:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - Same also full gear. Again one more time singing counting numbers. Sometimes noon have duty (wash meal bucket kind work) can makeup rest until two o&amp;rsquo;clock. Can upstairs dormitory steal listen downstairs how this military song sing. Obligatory service since often practice all can sing. But voluntary service since usually busy all not quite can sing. Overall depend on obligatory service pull high average value otherwise will be scolded by battalion duty officer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;14:10 ~ 16:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Training Class&lt;/strong&gt; - Continue doing things similar to morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;16:00 ~ 17:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Exercise&lt;/strong&gt; - Different from boot camp. Phase 2 has exercise time. Sometimes company commander mood good will come lead physical training. Otherwise usually run then go basketball court play ball. Really quite healthy life. Later I and few peers will long run to 542 camp area together. About three kilometers. Way back drop by Hi-Life steal buy something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;17:00 ~ 18:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dinner&lt;/strong&gt; - Eating same things as lunch. However voluntary service since have outside eating sleeping. So people eat not many.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;18:00 ~ 19:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Washing Up&lt;/strong&gt; - See you want wash bath this time or not. Not wash later also have chance. Not anxious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;19:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - This assembly only assemble obligatory service see person missing or not. Then find some things give obligatory service do at night. Most time just practice military song practice one hour or clean environment. Meet better duty squad leader assemble finish directly release us down rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;19:00 ~ 20:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Night Class&lt;/strong&gt; - Same as above. Just practice military song and clean. More special have night march and night shooting. But only each once. But is very rare experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;20:00 ~ 22:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Free Time&lt;/strong&gt; - Same just do whatever want. At this time not washed yet go wash. Otherwise rot in dormitory. Watch youtube, play phone, find girlfriend chat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;22:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Bedtime&lt;/strong&gt; - Bedtime turn off light. However want sleep or not is your business. Want play phone until dawn also fine. Sometimes also will ask outside eating sleeping voluntary service bring some good food from outside in this time eat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E8%8F%AF%E6%B0%91%E5%9C%8B%E9%99%B8%E8%BB%8D%E8%A3%9D%E7%94%B2%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94%E5%85%AB%E5%9B%9B%E6%97%85" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E8%8F%AF%E6%B0%91%E5%9C%8B%E9%99%B8%E8%BB%8D%E8%A3%9D%E7%94%B2%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94%E5%85%AB%E5%9B%9B%E6%97%85&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chenggong Ridge 158T 101 Brigade 4th Battalion Boot Camp Reflection</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/chenggong-ridge-158t-101-brigade-4th-battalion-boot-camp-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2022 13:32:31 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/chenggong-ridge-158t-101-brigade-4th-battalion-boot-camp-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/T828STy.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Chenggong Ridge 158T 101 Brigade 4th Battalion Boot Camp Reflection" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="chenggong-ridge-158t-101-brigade-4th-battalion-boot-camp-reflection"&gt;Chenggong Ridge 158T 101 Brigade 4th Battalion Boot Camp Reflection
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When writing this article, it has been about a month and a half since the end of boot camp, and there is still one month left before discharge. While the memory is not too distant, I record my impressions and thoughts on boot camp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="preface"&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be honest, until the month before I served in the army, I really didn&amp;rsquo;t think I would come in to serve as a regular soldier. At least since the physical examination, I maintained that after a few more re-examinations, I should be able to use flat feet to be a twelve-day supplementary soldier. In January of this year (2022), I got several pre-employment R&amp;amp;D alternate service offers, and probably thought that after graduation I should just go to the substitute service camp to sing songs and prepare to go to work. Later, I decided to go to a foreign company without R&amp;amp;D alternate service, and still felt that there should be a chance to be a supplementary soldier, because in August and September, my BMI once soared over 29, not far from the supplementary soldier standard. Who knew that later trapped in the deep waters of graduate school, a conscription order became the graduation password. Thinking about it is also absurd, never thought that one day I would look forward to the arrival of the conscription order so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my echo chamber, most people disapprove of spending four months serving in the army. Those who have served all think it is a waste of time, pulling weeds or cleaning every day, plus watching a group of idiot officers play tricks. Those with a master&amp;rsquo;s degree will also think that going to serve as R&amp;amp;D substitute service or even six months of general substitute service is better than four months without freedom. People who haven&amp;rsquo;t served might be able to say things like four months will pass quickly. Once you actually come in, you will regret how time can pass so slowly. Even now with only the last month left, I still feel that coming in is mostly a waste of time, only receiving 6000 yuan per month, which is really tragic compared to the salary outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly, my family was unusually excited about serving in the army. In their traditional concept, serving in the army is the real coming-of-age ceremony. For young people who think about going abroad all day, this may be the last chance to cultivate patriotism and love for the people. Plus the increasingly bloated figure during graduate school, going in for exercise should be friendly to health. Later when the conscription order came down and they knew I was going to Chenggong Ridge for boot camp, my father was even more excited. He served as an obligatory sergeant at Chenggong Ridge for nearly two years back then. Chenggong Ridge is a place where he invested his youth and is full of memories. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity that there is no family visit, otherwise it would be a good opportunity for him to come back and reminisce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From knowing that I might have a chance to serve in the army, to confirming which batch I was assigned to, and then getting the conscription order, all this happened within a month. There was no time to think, no time to change mindset. After discussing with the professor, I started running the graduation process. In between, stuck a five-day trip to Penghu, so that I was still arranging the oral defense time at night in the homestay. Returned from Penghu and spent a week completing the oral defense and leaving school procedures, and got the diploma on 9/19. Then three days later, on 9/21, I boarded the enlistment special train to Chenggong Ridge and started four months (16 weeks) of military life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="preparation"&gt;Preparation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since being busy with graduation was already overwhelming enough, I waited until I got my diploma to start thinking about serving in the army. Compared to some peers who may have waited for the conscription order for half a year, my preparation time was relatively very short. I roughly divided the preparation part into items and mentality, both are equally important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="essential-items"&gt;Essential Items
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone on the Internet said that you can actually enlist with just a wallet, because whatever you will use can be bought or obtained inside. This is true, but if you want to be more comfortable, it is better to prepare more things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="toiletries"&gt;Toiletries
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Toothbrush - Recommend bringing a few more. I brought an old one for the first week and it broke after two days, I could only ask for help from peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Toothpaste - Bring a bigger tube, better than having none to use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; 3-in-1 Shower Gel - Adidas is good to use, convenient is good, don&amp;rsquo;t be too particular.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Electric Shaver - Before going in, someone said electric ones cannot be brought. Chenggong Ridge seems to allow it. Much more convenient than manual ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Towel - No need to bring, the railing by the bed can only hang the officially issued one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="clothing"&gt;Clothing
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Underwear - Recommend bringing some more. Although there are issued ones, you may not be used to wearing them. Sometimes you may not be able to wash them on the same day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Undershirt - No need to bring, can only wear issued camouflage undershirt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Warm Clothing - When the weather is cold, you can wear thermal underwear or a jacket inside the camouflage jacket.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Casual Clothes - You can only wear casual clothes when going out for holidays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Laundry Bag - No need to bring, will be issued inside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="medicine"&gt;Medicine
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Vitamins - Can bring some Vitamin B or C. Can eat some when it&amp;rsquo;s tiring, recover faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Analgesic Antipyretic Tablets - Very often catch a cold and have a headache inside, can eat a little to relieve symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Band-Aid - Can use for injuries or blisters.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Salonpas Spray - Can use for muscle soreness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Peppermint Oil - Can use for headache.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="miscellaneous"&gt;Miscellaneous
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Wet Wipes - Bring cooling wet wipes, it&amp;rsquo;s a godsend when the weather is hot. Wiping once before nap makes it easy to sleep.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Books - Most of the time inside is spent waiting. Taking books out to read usually won&amp;rsquo;t be a problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Power Bank - Although time using mobile phone is very little, having a power bank can prevent phone from running out of power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Baby Powder - Can use when weather is hot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Small Fan - It is usually very hot inside the mosquito net, and most of the time the air conditioning cannot blow in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Flashlight - Usually need to get up early in the morning to organize internal affairs, but cannot turn on the light, can only rely on flashlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Earplugs - Must bring for target practice, and easy to lose. Not wearing earplugs for target practice will make your ears ring for a week, I experienced it personally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Pen - Ballpoint pen and permanent marker are needed. Better to have more because they are often lost. Used for writing Big Soldier diary or filling out forms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="food"&gt;Food
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Drinks - Usually not allowed to buy drinks from vending machines first few days after entering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Snacks - Same logic, eat some when homesick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Chewing Gum - Can eat when bored, but don&amp;rsquo;t be too high profile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="documents"&gt;Documents
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Original Conscription Order - Will be very troublesome if not brought.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Copy of Diploma - Just bring the highest degree, because degree will be used to distinguish drawing lots batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Certificate of Service Period Deduction - This needs to be applied for at the school military instruction office. Best to get it done before going in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Copy of Household Certificate - Wasn&amp;rsquo;t used later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Personal Chop - Spend some money to carve one, will be collected after entering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="money"&gt;Money
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Miscellaneous Fees - First week will collect a lot of money, like laundry fee, hair cutting fee, issued items fee etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Small Change - Will be used for vending machines and making phone calls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Phone Card - Don&amp;rsquo;t think there are many opportunities to use mobile phone. In boot camp stage you can only rely on phone card to contact outside world. Calling mobile phone is very expensive, suggest preparing more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="mentality-adjustment"&gt;Mentality Adjustment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is very difficult&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First of course is to convince yourself why you are here to serve these four months. Then is to understand what is done in each stage in the army, can relieve fear of ignorance. Before enlisting I kept watching &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P5dSNSErm3U&amp;amp;t=1940s" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Ah Zhe Soldier&lt;/a&gt; videos, inside explains very clearly what happens every week in boot camp. Knowing more can convince yourself that the most painful part has passed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then can chat more with friends who have finished serving, understand how to relieve depression, how to get along with peers and officers. I feel my mentality wasn&amp;rsquo;t completely adjusted when I went in, and also spent a lot of time adapting to the rhythm inside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, never bring outside things inside to complete, like preparing for exams, applying for schools or completing research etc. You will find that you can&amp;rsquo;t do anything inside. That sense of powerlessness is terrible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="life"&gt;Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I can verify positively that boot camp is absolutely the most, most, most painful period of time in the four months, especially the first ten days after entering. After surviving it, it will be like eating sugarcane, getting sweeter and smoother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="about-chenggong-ridge-and-101-brigade"&gt;About Chenggong Ridge and 101 Brigade
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="my-unit"&gt;My Unit
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;My assigned batch is &lt;strong&gt;Army 158T Military Training Service&lt;/strong&gt;, assigned unit is &lt;strong&gt;101 Brigade 4th Battalion Firepower Company&lt;/strong&gt;. It is said it is called Firepower Company because we are the fourth infantry company in this battalion. To avoid the word four, it was renamed Firepower Company. In the past it was called Weapons Company, don&amp;rsquo;t know why it was changed to Firepower Company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are about 150 military training soldiers in the company. Company level has Company Commander, Political Warfare Officer, Company Sergeant Major. Those responsible for managing us are several sergeants below Staff Sergeant taking turns being on duty. Can observe that the company is often understaffed, often only two or three sergeants managing 150 soldiers. Can be said to be willing but unable, often feel hard for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="about-chenggong-ridge"&gt;About Chenggong Ridge
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chenggong Ridge is an old boot camp center. The entire camp area is responsible for receiving new recruits. Very, very few combat units. Can feel that equipment in Chenggong Ridge is older, more biased towards training purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditionally Chenggong Ridge has 302 and 104 two brigades. Later after 101 Brigade was reinstated, it borrowed the original 104 Brigade barracks to station. Chenggong Ridge camp area is very large. Unless there are special reasons, moving around is by foot. When practicing target shooting, often walk from 104 to 302, takes about 30 minutes, and have to wear full gear with heavy &lt;em&gt;T65k2&lt;/em&gt; rifle. Very tiring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first floor of barracks usually has vending machines. This is the only place where we can freely buy things. There are also several camp stores and convenience stores inside the camp area. These are usually visible but not reachable. Only when going out for official duty can beg officers to take us there. So people who finished official duty will have bulging pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chenggong Ridge also has a substitute service training class. Usually pass by on the way to target practice. But suggest not to observe their life, mood will be bad. Their life is colorful, while ours is camouflage&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transportation in Chenggong Ridge is very, very convenient compared to other camp areas. Ten minutes walk from the main gate to Chenggong Train Station. Spending fifty yuan to take a taxi, can reach High Speed Rail station within ten minutes. In addition, thousands of people go out together when Chenggong Ridge has a holiday. Many people and there is a level crossing right at the gate. To prevent clogging when going out the gate, usually run out. Very spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="enlistment"&gt;Enlistment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On enlistment day, gathered at Taipei Main Station lobby. After gathering, people from district office will send everyone to the special train to Chenggong Ridge. That process is unforgettable forever. Hundreds of sad-faced boys gathered in the lobby, one look and you know what suffering they are going to encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The enlistment special train is a Ju-Guang train that drives very slowly. Slow enough to have time to eat a very terrible bento in the middle. Please remember this bento, because this will be the only warm food from the outside world you can eat for these ten days. About three hours later the train will arrive at New Wuri Station. Transfer to bus directly into Chenggong Ridge camp area. Then will gather and be assigned to respective companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Followed by assigning seat numbers. Everyone will circulate rumors to stand back as much as possible, don&amp;rsquo;t stand in the front row, because will be squad leader. I just happened to become number 005. The schedule on the first day will be very tight. First is security check (body search), arranging organization, issuing equipment, arranging beds, simply teaching everyone how to organize internal affairs. From this time on we have to say goodbye to our mobile phones, start primitive life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rmxmtCM.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/UjBL03T.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/TXTj3lQ.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Enlistment Special Train&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="schedule"&gt;Schedule
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life in the unit is very regular. If there are no special things, daily schedule is about the same. Therefore quite easy to grasp what will happen next. During boot camp period we live on summer time. Daily schedule is roughly as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;05:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Wake Up&lt;/strong&gt; - Although schedule says wake up at this time, usually have to get up earlier to fold quilt, mosquito net and wash up. These jobs actually take quite some time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;05:50&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - If nothing special, wear sports uniform and go downstairs to assemble at company assembly ground (the open space at barracks entrance). Suggest going down ten minutes earlier, because 05:50 is time for assembly completion, but someone is late every time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;06:00 ~ 06:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Breakfast&lt;/strong&gt; - Because many people, cafeteria cannot sit everyone, so we will split into two batches for cafeteria. When one batch goes to eat, the other batch will do environment cleaning. Breakfast usually is a bun with some dishes and tea. Occasionally there will be things like hamburgers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;07:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - This assembly requires full gear (helmet, S-belt).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;07:10 ~ 10:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Training Class&lt;/strong&gt; - Will have class according to schedule of the day. Things learned are mostly things that will be tested in assessment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;11:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - Yes, you will find you did nothing and going to eat again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;11:00 ~ 12:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Lunch&lt;/strong&gt; - Lunch has four dishes and one soup plus fruit. Standard is about same as elementary school nutritious lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;12:30 ~ 13:50&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Nap&lt;/strong&gt; - Since nothing to do can only sleep or read books. I usually go make a public phone call to girlfriend before nap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;14:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - Same also full gear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;14:10 ~ 16:30&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Training Class&lt;/strong&gt; - Continue doing things similar to morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;17:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - Time to eat again.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;17:00 ~ 18:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Dinner&lt;/strong&gt; - Eating same things as lunch. Dishes often not enough to eat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;18:00 ~ 19:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Washing Up&lt;/strong&gt; - At this time everyone will rush to grab showers. 150 people rushing for 20 showers easily causes traffic jam. Also will set up mosquito net on bed, to make sleeping time faster at night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;19:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly&lt;/strong&gt; - By this time most people finished showering. Wear sports uniform and assemble. Sometimes in Zhongshan room sometimes on company assembly ground.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;19:00 ~ 21:00&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Night Class&lt;/strong&gt; - Most of the time doing some very redundant things. Like collecting some money, data or issuing equipment. Other time just spacing out. Occasionally will give mobile phones, but probability is very low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="duty-officer"&gt;Duty Officer
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The duty officer of the week will largely determine if you live comfortably that week. Duty rotation order will be published on schedule. Can know who is on duty next, be mentally prepared. Duty officer usually hands over on Thursday afternoon. Each time there will be a &lt;strong&gt;Company Duty Officer&lt;/strong&gt; responsible for leading training progress, there will be a &lt;strong&gt;Duty Squad Leader&lt;/strong&gt; responsible for roll call and managing unit order. Being on duty feels like a very tiring job. One or two people manage 150 soldiers often cannot take care of everything. Officers on duty all want to get out quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good duty officer has clear standards, strict in appropriate situations, won&amp;rsquo;t play with soldiers arbitrarily. Bad duty officer has inconsistent standards, poor efficiency, drag everyone&amp;rsquo;s rest time. The week when it&amp;rsquo;s turn for bad or inexperienced duty officer will be smoky and full of complaints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="welfare"&gt;Welfare
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Things that are taken for granted outside will be a kind of welfare inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest Time&lt;/strong&gt; - Don&amp;rsquo;t doubt, they treat giving soldiers rest as a kind of welfare. You have to be more obedient to give you more rest time. Please remember the famous saying from squad leader&amp;rsquo;s mouth: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You cooperate with me, I cooperate with you, your rest time will only become more and more.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vending Machine&lt;/strong&gt; - Although there are vending machines downstairs every building, doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we have right to use vending machines. Officers will open vending machines depending on order. We started having right to use vending machines on third day. And not all vending machines can be used, only can use vending machine belonging to own company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smoking&lt;/strong&gt; - I don&amp;rsquo;t smoke, but share anyway. Smoking is also a welfare. Our company let people smoke on the second day. Everyone is afraid some people will start naughty without cigarettes. Smoking time is usually after lunch and dinner, gather at a place to smoke collectively. Since lighters are prohibited items, can only get from squad leader. Scene of dozen people borrowing fire from each other is very interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Phone&lt;/strong&gt; - Too little mobile phone time should be the place everyone most dissatisfied. We should only use mobile phone once or twice a week, about ten to twenty minutes each time. Usually when mobile phone cannot be used, locked in phone cabinet. Can see but cannot touch. In this era people addicted to mobile phones should be more than people addicted to cigarettes. Should be reasonable to give mobile phone opportunity comparable to smoking. Mobile phone needs to install National Army MDM to be used in camp area. Will help everyone install first few days. MDM software will lock camera and GPS. Can unlock after going out of camp area on holiday. Suggest trying not to bring non-ios phones in. MDM will be harder to install. Sometimes will affect your precious mobile phone usage time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camp Store&lt;/strong&gt; - Chenggong Ridge has three or four camp stores. Except for first day when taken collectively to buy daily necessities, likely won&amp;rsquo;t have opportunity to go again, unless on official duty. Chenggong Ridge recently renovating, so many moving things and cleaning jobs need manpower. Most of the time halfway through work officer will take us to camp store to buy something. Considered an unwritten welfare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id="punishment"&gt;Punishment
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where there is welfare there is punishment. And punishment can be collective or individual. Collective punishment is commonly known as &lt;strong&gt;Collective Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;. Several people in group behave poorly, will sequentially deprive above collective punishments. Let those few people be hated by everyone. For occasional especially disorderly behavior will have individual punishment. However since Hung Chung-chiu incident, corporal punishment is explicitly prohibited in army. Using running, push-ups etc. as punishment are all very serious behaviors. Should be no officer dare to take this risk. So adopt more static punishment methods. Below list punishment methods they can adopt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confession Letter&lt;/strong&gt; - This is first step of all punishments. Is a blank form asking you to write what bad things you did. After writing officer will punish further according to situation. Sometimes might just be bird things like clothes not worn, assembly late. To make up a thousand words is also painful enough. So often hear squad leader say: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Whoever XXX again send one confession letter each person, do what I say&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08&lt;/strong&gt; - If did something relatively serious wrong like late returning from holiday, mostly punishment start from holiday time. When we were in boot camp mostly could leave camp before Friday 18:00. Being punished 08 means can only leave camp next day 08:00. Thinking of sleeping alone in huge dormitory feels pitiful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Penalty Duty&lt;/strong&gt; - If you are 08 holiday that week, but you did foolish thing again, then might be penalty duty. Penalty duty once two hours. So you might become 10:00 to leave camp. Every minute of freedom outside is important when serving in army. Never joke with your holiday.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If reached illegal level, it is said directly forced to stay in camp until discharge, also accept military law trial. So never do bad things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="activity-space"&gt;Activity Space
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In boot camp stage, new recruits have completely no freedom. All our free activity space is limited to the floor belonging to company, including corridor toilet and dormitory. And only can move during rest time. Wanting to go downstairs or move to other places in camp area must be led by officer. Otherwise being spotted will be big trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, between companies, between battalions have very clear boundaries. Like cannot use toilet of other companies, cannot walk stairs of other companies, cannot cross central corridor of other battalions, walk assembly ground of other battalions etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="internal-affairs"&gt;Internal Affairs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In boot camp stage everything has to be regulated. Where to put what things how to put, how to fold quilt, what things can put cannot put etc. Order of shoe tray shoes cannot be wrong. Washbasin can only put toothbrush toothpaste. Toothbrush must be inserted in steel cup dirty enough used by unknown number of people. Direction facing must be same side. Towel can only hang officially issued label facing inside. In inner affairs cabinet clothes can only hang jackets and camouflage uniforms. Sleeves also need to be tied up. Cabinet top can only put helmet and S-belt. Mosquito net and quilt have fixed folding method. Edges and corners need to be pulled square like tofu. Only thing can be messy is inside Yellow Pu bag. If above not done well considered internal affairs not tidy. Too messy then sorry 08.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="recruitment"&gt;Recruitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Obligatory service is key recruitment target of National Army. At beginning of boot camp people from other units will come to camp to persuade everyone to sign voluntary service. They will come to introduce their unit location work and welfare. Usually will put on good food eaten everyday and newly built barracks to attract everyone. Also will promote stability of National Army salary and benefits of pension. In addition will also say now National Army all have eating and sleeping outside. Similar to working outside. However whether it is really so good is left for people who really signed to experience. Only know very few people can endure humiliation and burden for twenty years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole recruitment link luck good will last two three days. These few days no need training class. If you show willingness to sign after hearing, recruiter will pull you out for interview separately. Sometimes will even give you mobile phone, go to camp store etc. benefits. In addition if you almost decided to sign, first holiday can release 12 holiday i.e. leave camp Friday noon. Saying let you go convince parents let you sign. So also quite a lot of people pretend want to sign during this period. Try to get some benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After recruitment period ends will see peers who signed can enjoy various benefits like using mobile phone during rest time, playing ball time. Sometimes also no need to follow training class. Can only say National Army uses every means to attract everyone to join. But no need to envy them too much. They just cool for these few days. After phase two down to unit is another world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="holiday"&gt;Holiday
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holiday is the only chance for obligatory service to return to society outside. Unlike voluntary service occasionally can eat and sleep outside a bit. Obligatory service holiday in principle is rest when see red. So consecutive holidays rest as usual, make-up work make-up as usual. Boot camp first ten days no holiday. Afterward will make up two days holiday back. So first ten days are most painful. No freedom no mobile phone information completely separated from outside world. Our batch luckier just met Double Ten consecutive holiday. Plus two days holiday not taken. Our first three holidays were all consecutive three days. Considering this batch are all Taipei soldiers. Distance far. First three holidays also let us off 18 holiday. Therefore there were few weeks only trained four days class. Already lived quite well compared to other batches. Only last week off 08 holiday. Result caused public anger of peers. But military training service holiday time originally is Saturday 08. So nothing good to argue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chenggong Ridge holiday in and out all walk main gate. That is the section with road to success sign. Holiday will collectively lead team walk from barracks to main gate. Will first divide into taking taxi, Chenggong Train Station, parent pickup three blocks lead team separately. If going to High Speed Rail station walk taxi route. Then take taxi to High Speed Rail station 50 yuan per person. Short five minutes journey one car full can carry seven people. Actually quite profitable. High Speed Rail round trip Taipei is 700. So monthly 6000 yuan actually not quite enough for fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Returning from holiday enter from another closer gate. Suggest arriving Taichung High Speed Rail station early. Sometimes many people no taxi. And taxi cannot drive directly to gate. Only can drop off near gate. Remaining section of road walk in about 20 minutes. So try to be early for everything. Late returning from holiday is very serious. Also don&amp;rsquo;t make trouble on road walking into camp area. Will have officers patrolling. Being spotted also confession letter one sheet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="training-class"&gt;Training Class
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since boot camp time is very short, training class items focus on assessment items. Basic attire for training class is helmet + S-belt. Most training classes not tiring. About junior high school PE class level. And after some incidents officers also don&amp;rsquo;t dare to train soldiers randomly. You propose (dizziness, foot pain etc.) basically will let you rest. Going to toilet same just say will let you go. They also afraid you complain him. Weather influence more terrible than officers. Didn&amp;rsquo;t encounter rain in Chenggong Ridge. Considered very lucky. Heard other units individual combat in rain. Getting mud all over body. Summer sun is terrible. Can only rely on drinking water to cool down. Training classes I experienced roughly have following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="opening-ceremony"&gt;Opening Ceremony
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fifth day just entered will have an opening ceremony. Is bringing all Chenggong Ridge new recruits to assembly ground to sunbathe. Will have high officials like Brigade Commander to watch. During period will have to read some soldier oath. To proceed opening smoothly. Will spend whole morning practicing organizing team and standing at attention. Sun still very big in September. Should be quite a lot of people heatstroke from sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="bayonet-charge"&gt;Bayonet Charge
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bayonet charge can be said to be most important item of assessment. But compared to target practice, individual combat actually quite useless. Same set of things hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed for thirty forty years. This era on battlefield also should be very hard to rely on bayonet technique to stab enemy to death. Understanding as a team performance might be more acceptable. Can show team tacit understanding and morale. Can refer to &lt;a class="link" href="https://youtu.be/Vm95nZkKeZc" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Rookie Diary Bayonet Charge clip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayonet charge whole performance about five minutes. Will take about three to four mornings to practice. Will see group of people holding T65k2 rifles turning around shouting &amp;ldquo;Kill!&amp;rdquo;. Most terrible part of practicing bayonet charge lies in extending hand straight to hold gun when stabbing gun out. When practicing continuous movement squad leader sometimes deliberately doesn&amp;rsquo;t call next movement. Rifle very heavy. About four kilograms. Maintaining state of stabbing gun out tests arm muscle endurance very much. Hand can be sour for several days after practice. In addition team tacit understanding also needs time to cultivate. Like scattering and assembling. Also bayonet charge flow needs to be familiar. Watching other companies stab can still see people stab wrong side, slow half beat or run wrong place when positioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="grenade"&gt;Grenade
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grenade throwing can be divided into two parts: basic throwing and field throwing. Basic throwing is simpler. Just throw a practice grenade about 500 grams into a fan-shaped area then lie down. Actually throwing is quite difficult. Small practice grenade heavier than imagined. Usually if not throwing things, hard to apply force correctly will throw not far. Therefore some people can easily throw very far some people throw very hard still not into 25 meters. Training class will first explain steps and throwing method. But no one understands. Actually as long as can throw out. Movement random throw also fine. But surely remember to lie down. Not lie down will definitely be blasted by squad leader. Grenade class considered very relaxed. Only one venue. One company 150 people one person go up throw one or two times three hours passed. Other time just sit on bench watch others throw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interesting is sometimes go compete throwing grenade with other companies. Will pick few stronger ones from company to represent. Lose whole company do push-ups 30 times. Once won squad leader even treated people who went up to throw drinks. Considered more interesting part in boredom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Field is to throw grenade into a square window. Simulating situation of attacking enemy hiding place in actual combat. Field throwing very hard to throw in without practice. After all only touched practice grenade once or twice. To accurately control throwing direction and force very difficult. Remember only five or six people in whole company really threw in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="target-practice"&gt;Target Practice
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Target practice uses National Army T65K2 rifle to shoot human-shaped target. Can be divided into 25 meters zeroing shooting and 175 meters shooting. Distance farther shooting difficulty higher. Boot camp target practice all adopt prone position. But heard actually not much used in actual combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because guns plus bullets are very dangerous. Range strictly requires discipline. Cannot laugh play sleep randomly. Also have to be very familiar with shooting flow. Therefore before target practice will do shooting preview several times. Which is simulating target practice flow. Including how to prone shoot correctly, how to open safety, how to aim, how to press gun, how to load bullets, how to clear check gun. And commands on range like what left line ready right line ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure everyone knows then will take to range for formal shooting. Battalion commander company commander will all be there when target shooting. Usually company commander serves as shooting commander. Will give shooting commands. Range usually has several target positions. One target position corresponds to one human-shaped target. Beside target position will have range assistant assist shooting. Help catch shell casing hand magazine and prevent you from doing outrageous foolish things. Before going up to shoot will arrange wave target position. Shoot wave by wave up target platform. Each time will shoot about one to three magazines. Each time about six bullets. Thought gun recoil huge before shooting. Actually okay. Sound is very loud. Louder than all firecrackers you heard. Therefore target practice must wear earplugs. Once I forgot to wear earplugs for target practice. Ears rang directly after first shot. Ringing feeling only eliminated after a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target practice itself actually not tiring. Most time at range waiting for others to finish shooting. And because range discipline stricter. Cannot chat cannot do other things. Very boring. Target practice more tiring is preparation work. Prior need to pick up gun from warehouse. Then check gun. Range is at Chenggong Ridge 302. Carry heavy rifle walk thirty minutes from barracks. Walk until tired. Finish shooting take team walk back. Check gun clear gun again. Then send gun at night. Sometimes have to queue gun sentry guard gun. Often waste whole day for shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="individual-combat"&gt;Individual Combat
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individual combat is simulating really going to battlefield to fight. Considered more useful class. Boot camp receives rifleman training. And rifleman role is to annihilate enemy firepower on ground. And individual combat teaches everyone how to use alternating fire cover. Attack forward towards enemy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individual combat field looks like a forest. Then will arrange several stations. Each station will have several situations. Such as have barbed wire, have trench how to cover each other pass. When our side someone injured how to rescue him and send back. And when two armies engage how to charge forward. Among there will be very many report words to memorize. Remember also memorized for several days. Result actual assessment different from what everyone memorized. Ran through all individual combat in a mess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually doing will have quite a lot parts need to lie on ground or crawl forward. Therefore be mentally prepared whole body covered with mud and strange bugs crawl on body. During assessment will also set up machine gun tower firing blank ammo and use TNT to simulate mortar. Scene very shocking. Can slightly feel battlefield situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="assessment"&gt;Assessment
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week of boot camp is assessment week. About three days will conduct assessment. Meaning of assessment is to test whether unit has combat ability. Test includes physical fitness and combat skills. Physical fitness is push-ups, sit-ups and 3000 meters. Combat skills is bayonet charge, grenade, individual combat and target practice. Assessment doing things just doing things done in training class again. Just beside will have instructor from test center to supervise. Assessment officer will be stricter. Actually still going through a motion. After all five weeks time really hard to say every item practiced very skillfully. Officer also understands this. Therefore also doesn&amp;rsquo;t care too much about grades. Only care whether tried best to participate and whether order is good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for whether pass assessment makes any difference. One saying is pass will be easier to be call-up. But also some people say fail easier to call-up. Anyway just an urban legend. Only certain thing is assessment record will stay until unit, call-up until discharge. Later discovered by people assessment failed should be a bit shameful. So better try best to pass. As for physical fitness really cannot or really don&amp;rsquo;t want to sunburn there is exempt skill test move. Can find a chronic illness on body (flat feet, old injury, high blood pressure etc.) can go to National Army Hospital (&lt;em&gt;Note not Tri-Service General Hospital nor Veterans General Hospital&lt;/em&gt;) open exempt skill test certificate. Haven&amp;rsquo;t heard anyone failed yet. Have exempt skill test certificate these three days just watch others skill test. Even more absolute can say body uncomfortable first day of assessment. Officer won&amp;rsquo;t force you must complete test. Anyway soldier is about honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="official-duty"&gt;Official Duty
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;During our boot camp other units preparing to renovate barracks. Need strictly large amount of people help move. Just happen obligatory service is cheapest labor. Therefore we have many opportunities to go on official duty. Boot camp stage official duty must go. Because not going is training class. Training class boredom level not as interesting as moving things. In addition official duty sometimes have welfare. Like vending machine, smoking, camp store etc. Also can take this opportunity to look at other places in camp area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="drawing-lots"&gt;Drawing Lots
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t know from which batch phase two training need to go to other units. Then had this drawing lots link. Drawing lots everyone most afraid is drawing Golden Horse Prize. And current drawing lots system will first let people who really want to go to outlying islands volunteer priority. Remaining quota then let everyone draw. Surprisingly volunteer outlying islands registration quite enthusiastic. Probably think go only more than two months. Treat as working holiday in outlying islands should be nice. Except outlying islands. Maybe considering this batch all Taipei soldiers. Other lots almost all northern lots. Few farther ones like Hualien. Drawing lots link is everyone go up to lot cylinder draw a number plate. Someone will tell you drew what lot. More interesting is after drawing everyone ask each other what drew and find companion for next unit. Also somewhat sentimental. Drawing lots decided boot camp companions sharing weal and woe phase two training also separate. Phase two training compared to boot camp will be much relaxed. So actually most lots result actually similar. At most accommodation environment better or closer to home. I later drew &lt;strong&gt;Hsinchu Hukou Armored 584 Brigade&lt;/strong&gt;. Already considered lot farther from Taipei. Later have chance write feeling about phase two training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reflection"&gt;Reflection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Say unreservedly boot camp is the most, most, most hard period of time in these four months. Still remember girlfriend suddenly confirmed diagnosed could not send me to serve army before enlistment. Let my every day next only spiritual pillar is time calling her public phone every day. Everyday besides solid training class make muscle sore. Next is just deprived freedom from free world instantly. Managed by others like elementary student. Really makes people doubt life. Doubt myself why waste four months managed by people. Regret why chose substitute service. In addition deprived mobile phone. Completely disjointed from outside information. What happened changed outside this month nothing can know. Lack of information very terrifying. Cannot contact girlfriend, family, friends moment to moment also makes people anxious. Also happen to approach election. What that candidate did said we also cannot know. Maybe because deprived freedom. Make people cherish value of freedom more. Cherish holiday time. Also warn myself don&amp;rsquo;t do bad things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although officer management standard inconsistent, work efficiency extremely poor. Food terrible and often not enough to eat. This is still an unforgettable time. In hard times remember any interesting people things more. Without coming in to serve army might never know people of other backgrounds in society. Very hard to communicate with them without stereotype. And serving army broke barrier. Let me have broader understanding of this society. Now looking back. One month boot camp is absurd yet interesting. Boring yet meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/CAp589g.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Me one week after enlistment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below record some unforgettable people things in boot camp:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="unforgettable-things"&gt;Unforgettable Things
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id="0600"&gt;0600
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Winter time is 6:00 wake up. Every day wake up duty squad leader will broadcast: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Current time 0600, Firepower Company wake up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, this probably most unwanted sound for all new recruits. This means leaving dreamland. Get up wash fold mosquito net quilt. Welcome another boring day. It is said after discharge still some people subconsciously exist fear of &lt;a class="link" href="https://youtu.be/KUOGEFu7qLw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Reveille&lt;/a&gt;. Hearing this sound still cannot help but nervous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fearing this sound not without reason. Boot camp stage quite a lot of people sleep not very well. Even 09:30 force everyone lie on bed. Still various reasons can make people can&amp;rsquo;t sleep. Like weather hot mosquito net hangs. Air conditioning or fan basically can&amp;rsquo;t blow in. Will make people hot to unable sleep. Also snoring sound of peer often annoying. Result actual sleeping time only left about five six hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="bench"&gt;Bench
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Military training service carry-on equipment besides helmet, S-belt, water bottle. Also one must carry is bench. Provided by our company is a plastic square bench. When marching can just jam body waist carry with left hand. Whether training class, listening lecture recruitment or going to restaurant eat bench is essential item. Otherwise you can only sit on ground. Therefore we self-mock bench is our real organic weapon. Worthy of &lt;a class="link" href="https://youtu.be/NGLePv55Q4M" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;First of Seven Weapons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bench makes people so impressive. Besides accompany us one month. Also commands related to bench. Like sitting bench cannot sit directly. Wait for squad leader command &amp;ldquo;Place bench&amp;rdquo;. Place bench behind heel hand touch bench look at squad leader. Hear &amp;ldquo;Good&amp;rdquo; then can sit. At this time definitely have fool haven&amp;rsquo;t heard good sit. Will be scolded by squad leader then back to previous move. Like this place bench game sometimes can play ten minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="confirmed-diagnosis"&gt;Confirmed Diagnosis
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In normal world accidentally confirmed diagnosed covid-19 might be very worried. Because quarantined several days (at that time quarantine seven days) cannot go out. However in army confirmed diagnosis basically like winning lottery. At this time army policy is once confirmed diagnosis go home isolate seven days until rapid test positive can return. In addition close contact of same bed also can isolate seven days. Can take seven days holiday who wants to stay in boring unit. Therefore every time collective rapid test pray self or same bed rapid test plate can appear two lines. And people who hit really cheer like winning lottery. Will definitely be scolded by squad leader. But going out to easy seven days. Who cares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have to say army really is big virus den. More than one hundred people squeezed in small dormitory. Virus not spread also difficult. So first week appeared massive confirmed diagnosis. Plus same bed close contact about 60 people quarantined. My organic squad originally had 17 people. After first week only left five people including me. Originally thought 005 should be nothing related to squad leader. Result 001-004 all quarantined. I was forced to be squad leader more than week. Although squad leader also nothing to do. Since close contact will be quarantined. Someone in company originally close contact isolate seven days isolate finish find confirmed diagnosis isolate another seven days. Seven days later still not turn negative continue isolate. Result five weeks boot camp actual stay less than one week. Easy makes people envy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="rice-not-enough"&gt;Rice Not Enough
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Army food roughly junior high school nutritious lunch level. Won&amp;rsquo;t be hard to swallow but didn&amp;rsquo;t delicious to memorable. Compared to dish delicious or not everyone cares more is dish enough or not. Whole company has 150 people share that few five buckets of dish can be said monks many gruel little. Need someone strictly control everyone&amp;rsquo;s dish amount. Therefore also need special adding dish link let those appetite bigger add some dish eat fuller. However also often have fool steal dish when squad leader haven&amp;rsquo;t shouted add dish. Later of course scolded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later weeks of boot camp. Dish not enough situation more and more serious. Not our appetite getting bigger. But kitchen share us less and less dish. Later less than half people serve dish gone. Therefore someone called 1985 because of this. 1985 is National Army complaint phone. Just to avoid officer misconduct after Hung Chung-chiu incident. Once receive 1985 complaint. Superior officer must handle this matter. Therefore sometimes used as one of means revenge officer. Because dish not enough call 1985 also have this meaning. Therefore day of incident officer also agreed take us to camp store supplement nutrition. Later this matter went to brigade headquarters. Even brigade political warfare director came to concern this matter. He probably thought very baffling even this kind of matter call 1985. Or say &amp;ldquo;This is normal channel reflecting situation&amp;rdquo;. But still hope we can first reflect to company officer. They probably also think this kind of matter annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="holiday-return"&gt;Holiday Return
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Serving army most unforgettable probably holiday return time. Holiday rejoice self about to obtain short freedom time. RETURN lament why holiday passed so fast. And return with peer also make this matter become more interesting. Since High Speed Rail station to camp area take taxi. Peers often agree meet at High Speed Rail station. Eat Mos Burger or McDonald together. Enjoy last freedom time. Then take taxi. Walk into most unwanted return Chenggong Ridge camp area. On road everyone chat what played what ate during holiday. Then guess next week whether happy or painful. Outside everyone more or less have a career. Back to camp area just left a number. This transition road someone accompany also not that painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="dropping-chopsticks"&gt;Dropping Chopsticks
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boot camp stage up down restaurant collective lead team. In marching process as long as someone drops chopsticks. Sound will be very loud. At this time everyone knows someone chopsticks dropped. Interesting is from first day of boot camp to last day always someone cannot hold chopsticks well. Looks like Chenggong Ridge should think a way let everyone chopsticks not drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="squad-leader-emotional-blackmail"&gt;Squad Leader Emotional Blackmail
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Squad leader also human. Some squad leaders mood not good and glass heart. Boot camp time very short. And teach many assessment items. For squad leader already collapse enough. Among individual combat is hardest subject. Teach time only two mornings. Content very much. And squad leader teach very tired new recruits listen not listen. Teach second day squad leader probably teach very unhappy. Just directly said he doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to teach ran to smoke. Later scolded by duty officer plus prone on ground prone thirty minutes. Squad leader willing continue come back teach finish. Naturally learning effect very poor. Assessment everyone running randomly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="constipation"&gt;Constipation
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Army environment very magical. Once come in several days won&amp;rsquo;t want poop. Probably because army life too tight. Anytime wary whether accidentally miss assembly time. Under time pressure stomach probably not dare arbitrary. In addition no mobile phone accompany stomach not want work. At least these few weeks in boot camp times poop in camp area countable with fingers. Still comfortable poop at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="unforgettable-people"&gt;Unforgettable People
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since our squad too many people quarantined. Left five people have feeling sympathize with each other. Therefore first familiar with this group. Probably because this batch all Taipei soldiers. Most soldiers family background very good. Degree also very good. Have gangster but quantity compared other batches should be much less. Below record some unforgettable peers:
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/4VBuHro.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="internal-affairs-fool"&gt;Internal Affairs Fool
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every unit definitely has fool exist. And our company same no exception. Most impressive is a certain fool internal affairs untidy let officer temper blow up event. Everyone living habit different. Someone likes tidy link. Someone used to chaotic environment. If happen not good at organizing. Then in army really very painful. That fool is member of rice squad. Usually rest time compared average person came less. Therefore didn&amp;rsquo;t organize internal affairs much. Helmet put randomly. Yellow Pu bag whole bag exposed outside bed. Quilt not folded inside still run out. Messy until same bed cannot stand. Neighbor also cannot save him. Naturally scolded by squad leader. Plus confession letter one sheet. Later slightly improved. But compared others still failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="gangster"&gt;Gangster
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Army includes people of all shades. Also include some only junior high school graduated. Body tattoo dragon phoenix or carry several criminal records. Also because these people discover voluntary service standard actually quite strict. People with above situation voluntary service not accept. Usually these people will gather together smoke. Considered birds of a feather flock together. Average person rare chance contact them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once official duty accidentally heard them chat nearby. Discussing each other why caught need often run court. One said drunk driving caught. Another said gathering brawl heavy injury. Also one drug trafficking caught. Caught because drug user controlled by police want to hang drug dealer out. Before discovered him strange still forced go buy. He said don&amp;rsquo;t sell people point gun at you. Listen them talk can feel this society maybe not as bright and beautiful as we see. Still exist many dark corners. Family background not good or know wrong people easy make people go wrong way. These things if not come in serve army. Probably lifetime won&amp;rsquo;t hear personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="super-high-degree-peer"&gt;Super High Degree Peer
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I thought NTU EE CS master already considered very good degree. But this batch degree really exceeded my expectation. Our squad has 17 people. Inside contain two NTU medicine department and one TMU medicine department. Two NTU graduated. Other only two people no university degree. If promotion is random sampling then really quite big deviation. Again explain Taipei soldier family background good. Also value education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="peer-cannot-write-chinese"&gt;Peer Cannot Write Chinese
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides high degree peer. Also quite a lot people have study abroad experience. In our squad five people have study abroad experience. Someone high school go Germany exchange. Someone go study Lausanne Management Institute. Also someone go abroad research and study dentistry. More special is one from small study international school in Shanghai (heard therefore investigated background) then university go US study ABC. Although can speak Chinese but completely cannot read write Chinese. Therefore we need often help him translate translate. Besides often hear him talk about US things and discuss longing want go work in US in future. Let me also know quite a lot information during this period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/T828STy.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One month plus boot camp. Days like years inside. Now look actually tooth bite passed. Later might still miss time chat all night with same bed. Sweat bayonet charge together. Complain officer days. Maybe because all wasting time doing same thing. If want me go again I certainly unwilling.
Just entered still set many goals for self. Like physical fitness better. Weight lighter etc. After few days change mind live cool more important. Next batch after we left. Same unit had military training service accident. Now feel can safe discharge is luck&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/9DQU9KM.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Goodbye Chenggong Ridge~&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>