<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Summicron40mm on Hsing-Yu Shih</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/tags/summicron40mm/</link><description>Recent content in Summicron40mm on Hsing-Yu Shih</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 14:52:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hugoshih.com/tags/summicron40mm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Vintage Lenses - Leica Summicron-C 40mm f2</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/playing-with-vintage-lenses-leica-summicron-c-40mm-f2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 14:52:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/p/playing-with-vintage-lenses-leica-summicron-c-40mm-f2/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rx11Znm.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Playing with Vintage Lenses - Leica Summicron-C 40mm f2" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="playing-with-vintage-lenses---leica-summicron-c-40mm-f2"&gt;Playing with Vintage Lenses - Leica Summicron-C 40mm f2
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="preface"&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this era, poor students who want to play with the M system have many choices. Cheap and affordable 7Artisans, TTArtisan; diverse choices of Voigtländer; Zeiss whose image quality is not inferior to Leica at all; there are even flocks of ancient times M mount, L39 mount vintage lenses to choose from. Most 50mm focal lengths can be collected for just over 10,000, each is very good, each is full of stories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One rainy afternoon in 2020, nesting in the darkroom developing films, while exchanging equipment with other club members. I still remember a friend mysteriously took out his Leica M3 from his bag for me to touch. That heavy feel, solid shutter, suddenly understood why it is said once touched cannot go back. For several nights after going back, I was always thinking about this camera. Before long, I also bought the first Leica film camera in my life. Just buying it spent most of my savings. Could only &lt;del&gt;casually&lt;/del&gt; get a &lt;em&gt;7Artisans 35mm f2&lt;/em&gt; to fill hunger. Even though outsiders say how high the CP value of this lens is, heart was still very unsatisfied. And indeed photos taken were also very ordinary. Used Leica body, anyway have to match a Leica original lens. At least I want to experience what is called &amp;ldquo;German flavor&amp;rdquo; what is called Leica aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later encountered this Leica Summicron-C 40mm f2 on online trading platform. Condition not considered too good, paint loss coating scratches etc. problems all exist. Price therefore not too expensive, impression is around 14,000. Honest German made, Leica design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/mWW7v7E.jpg" width="33%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/3OWj30N.jpg" width="33%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/lxz6JIR.jpg" width="33%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This lens originally took a low price route. Mainly designed for use with Leica&amp;rsquo;s M system budget model Leica CL at that time. Leica CL is also a camera with quite a story. In Leica&amp;rsquo;s most desolate era, cooperated with Minolta to produce body with more electronic parts to attract users. Coping to let more people feel charm of Leica and purchase other Leica products. Result public instead only willing to purchase lower priced Leica CL and not willing to purchase Leica M5 at that time. Had to let Leica discontinue this camera early. And Summicron-C 40mm also only produced for few generations with camera then discontinued. Although said only produced for few generations, but production volume still quite large. Still considered easy to see on market today. Smaller body compared to other M models also makes many people love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d5/Leica_CL_avec_Summicron-C.JPG/300px-Leica_CL_avec_Summicron-C.JPG"
loading="lazy"
&gt;[1]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although said budget model, but imaging of this Summicron-C 40mm is still not bad. Also considered comparable to other standard lenses of Leica at that time. Therefore everyone would rather buy this budget model. Materials of this lens are also comparable to other Leica lenses. Specifications as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number: 11542&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Production Years: 1973-1979&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantity: 54,350&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mount: M mount&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lens: 6 elements in 4 groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aperture: f/2 - f/16, 10 blades&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight: 120g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of this lens, some people will call it &lt;em&gt;Small Seven Elements&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Poor Man&amp;rsquo;s Seven Elements&lt;/em&gt;. Nothing but similar focal length seeking a good name. But personally think there is still quite a gap with real Seven Elements. To say closer should be Leica Six Elements. Two lenses both are Double Gauss 6 elements in 4 groups structure. Production years also very close (1971-1979). In coating technology should also be very close. Except focal length difference two lenses actually very similar. Just pity Six Elements always jokingly called cost down version of Eight Elements after all lacking 2 elements. And produced in Leica&amp;rsquo;s most desolate era. Back to Summicron-C 40mm. Using 1/2 price of Six Elements to buy optical comparable to Six Elements. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it smell good? The C on nameplate marked its fate. Hard not to let people think of &lt;del&gt;Cheap&lt;/del&gt;. Just like iPhone 5c (people who can say this phone seem not young anymore).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/images/6/64/M-40f2-c.jpg" width="35%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/images/thumb/f/f5/Sc402.jpg/80px-Sc402.jpg" width="15%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/images/thumb/7/76/M35f2iii.jpg/250px-M35f2iii.jpg" width="26%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/images/thumb/2/26/S352%2B%2B.jpg/120px-S352%2B%2B.jpg" width="20%" alt="Image description" &gt;[2]
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volume is also big advantage of this lens. This lens can completely be called pancake lens. Volume even smaller than those Color-Skopar lenses produced by Voigtländer. And and and also have f2 aperture. As far as I know, this should also be smallest Summicron lens in Leica lens group. Have to admire Leica&amp;rsquo;s ability to play with Double Gauss structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because it is too excellent (too similar to Six Elements). Leica had to do a little modification to it. One is filter thread although same 39mm but cannot use normal 39mm filter but use special S5.5 pitch filter. But want force generic 39mm filter also can. Just might damage screw thread. Or cannot take down. In addition this lens also matched with hood. But is rubber made retractable hood. Maybe convenient but really ugly. When I collected lens didn&amp;rsquo;t attach this hood. If have I probably won&amp;rsquo;t install either. Later found a replica Leica hood install on. Appearance looks decent. I am a person won&amp;rsquo;t use lens cap if have hood. Forgetting to take down lens cap on rangefinder camera really nightmare. Having hood somewhat can prevent me touching lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another difference is mount. If this lens installed on M body will automatically bring out 50mm frameline. One saying is small mechanism Leica made to make this lens harder use on M body. However this small mechanism can be avoided through a little manual work. That is grind off bottom lug in picture a little can let it bring out 35mm frameline. Leica&amp;rsquo;s 35mm frameline is closer to 40mm focal length. Therefore having 35mm frameline will be much convenient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/ykBz44W.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/w4kOA9M.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other differences like focus tab different from traditional crescent changed to a peculiar triangle. Aperture ring carries a little damping. However each Leica lens aperture feel not quite same. Even same series lenses have little gap. Worthy of purely hand assembled and tuned lens.
Next lets see how this lens actually shoots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sample-shots"&gt;Sample Shots
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First use Portra take few shots. Try how strongest negative film performs
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/N7PsuhB.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Tq0c1ZH.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/BvouQEu.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can discover under sufficient light condition. Lens sharpness, bokeh basically no need worry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DJW0eLt.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/h95Yg5B.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portrait performance under low light still very good. Can note when aperture fully open. Small halo will appear in bright parts. May come from defect of coating technology in that era. Some people also call Holy Light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use valvia 100f take few more. Try performance on positive film
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/pMlD9S0.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/CO0rIaQ.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/1vCx614.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Indoor performance also very good. Color thick flavor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change scene try how landscape
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/JCQqqHJ.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/CbsYOAf.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/X8mxpyc.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally landscape on Provia 100f positive film&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/cL2urdu.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/OuvyS9w.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/2pexZV0.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As my first Leica lens. It accompanied me walk through many places. I also used it record many memories. Have to say it is a good lens. Also let me know Leica aesthetics through it. But it also has slight drawbacks. Like not near not far 40mm focal length, Holy Light etc. Later after acquiring Summicron-M 35mm ASPH resold Summicron-C 40mm. After all optical performance of two still has large gap. Still look forward one day in future have chance buy back this lens full of memories for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="reference"&gt;Reference
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[1] &lt;a class="link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leica_CL" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leica_CL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2] &lt;a class="link" href="http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/index.php/35mm_f/2_Summicron_III" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;http://www.l-camera-forum.com/leica-wiki.en/index.php/35mm_f/2_Summicron_III&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>