<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hasselblad on Hsing-Yu's Space</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/en/tags/hasselblad/</link><description>Recent content in Hasselblad on Hsing-Yu's Space</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 23:52:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hugoshih.com/en/tags/hasselblad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Playing with Vintage Lenses - Hasselblad Carl Zeiss CB 60mm f3.5</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/en/p/playing-with-vintage-lenses-hasselblad-carl-zeiss-cb-60mm-f3.5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 23:52:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/en/p/playing-with-vintage-lenses-hasselblad-carl-zeiss-cb-60mm-f3.5/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/c5as5mB.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Playing with Vintage Lenses - Hasselblad Carl Zeiss CB 60mm f3.5" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="playing-with-vintage-lenses---hasselblad-carl-zeiss-cb-60mm-f35"&gt;Playing with Vintage Lenses - Hasselblad Carl Zeiss CB 60mm f3.5
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="preface"&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the camera consumer market, the king in lens field besides &lt;strong&gt;Leica&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Carl Zeiss&lt;/strong&gt; lenses are also equally outstanding. Zeiss, known as optics giant, through powerful optical design strength developed various classic optical structures dominating until today in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first Zeiss lens was &lt;strong&gt;Distagon ZF 35mm f2&lt;/strong&gt; designed for &lt;strong&gt;Nikon F&lt;/strong&gt; mount. Classic retrofocus structure has excellent distortion control. Classic Zeiss T* coating controls contrast and sharpness just right. Just pity huge lens body really hard to accept. Sold this lens after using for a while. Nevertheless, I still looked forward to day returning to Zeiss embrace. So I later was easily pushed into pit of &lt;strong&gt;Hasselblad&lt;/strong&gt;. About how I was pushed into Hasselblad pit can refer to this: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.hugoshih.com/p/mechanical-camera-series-hasselblad-a12-magazine-loading-method/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Hasselblad A12 Magazine Loading Method&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Hasselblad, have to mention series of medium format classic lenses Carl Zeiss designed and manufactured for it. Directly let Hasselblad cameras rank among cameras of optical peak. Became artifact for landscape and commercial photography. Even later brought to moon together with lenses. From this can see power of Zeiss lenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In world of Hasselblad most common is that classic 80mm f2.8 standard lens. Equivalent to about 50mm on medium format. Having larger aperture and familiar and easy to master focal length. Became Hasselblad&amp;rsquo;s most popular entry lens. However I didn&amp;rsquo;t choose this lens. Main reason lies in premium of this lens in market too high. Also focal length too common. I want picture relatively different from others. Just under some coincidence I accidentally bumped into this &lt;strong&gt;CB 60mm f3.4&lt;/strong&gt;. Equivalent 35mm small wide angle meets my needs for street photography. Also this is known as one of sharper lenses in Hasselblad system. Under comprehensive consideration chose this lens as my &lt;strong&gt;Hasselblad 500C/M&lt;/strong&gt; hanging lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/pFS1Mbr.jpg" width="45%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/w3nnoFw.jpg" width="45%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Hasselblad camera and lens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zeiss worthy of optics giant. Having classic optical designs to overcome various engineering problems. And &lt;strong&gt;Distagon&lt;/strong&gt; optical structure in Zeiss lens history is as impressive as &lt;strong&gt;Biogon&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Planar&lt;/strong&gt;. Distagon is Zeiss&amp;rsquo;s retrofocus structure. Since SLR cameras like &lt;strong&gt;Nikon FM2&lt;/strong&gt; and Hasselblad must have a mirror behind lens to reflect lens image to viewfinder. &lt;strong&gt;Flange distance&lt;/strong&gt; meaning distance between camera lens mount and focal plane. Will be much longer than rangefinder cameras like Leica. This influence not big for telephoto lenses. Because telephoto lens own design can make last element of lens far from focal plane. However for wide angle lens this is much difficult. Like Schneider classic &lt;strong&gt;Angulon&lt;/strong&gt; design on Leica last element of lens almost sticking to Leica camera shutter curtain. If use this lens on SLR camera definitely will be hit by flipping mirror. Therefore a structure able to move out back focal distance and able to achieve wide angle effect must be invented. Therefore appeared Distagon this kind retrofocus structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/fXpwuKr.jpg" width="30%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leica&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Super-Angulon 21mm f/4&lt;/strong&gt; lens&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retrofocus structure as name suggests is opposite relative to telephoto structure. Design is based on inverted telescope optical path. Traditional telescope usually uses a set of convex lenses to collect and concentrate light at a point. Then use a set of concave lenses to spread these lights. To magnify image observer sees. However, retrofocus lens design adopts opposite concept. Use a concave mirror at front of lens to collect as wide light as possible. Then concentrate light then expand with convex lens at lens tail. This design allows lens better correct aberration. And able to make incident light closer perpendicular to sensor plane. Thereby providing clearer, more precise image. &lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://photographylife.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/Leica-APO-Telyt-M-135mm-f3.4-ASPH-Diagram.jpg" width="45%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;img src="https://i1.wp.com/pic3.zhimg.com/50/6ec4332bd79560f6ba5ca9e38279b496_hd.png" width="45%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Left is Leica 135mm APO telephoto structure, right is Zeiss Distagon retrofocus structure &lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id="fnref:4"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However disadvantage of retrofocus structure also obvious. Due to need use large amount of lenses to correct. Makes this kind of lens volume relatively large. Comparable to size of telephoto lens. In addition more lenses also bring more aberrations. Wide angle distortion effect retrofocus lens can achieve still not as good as those wide angle lenses designed sticking to focal plane. Therefore later Hasselblad specially designed specialized body for Zeiss Biogon lens which is &lt;strong&gt;Hasselblad 903 SWC&lt;/strong&gt;. From this can see such design still has status Distagon cannot replace. Furthermore like Zeiss Hologon lens with extremely high legendary color. Only used four elements achieved nearly perfect 15mm wide angle structure is genius design. Pity cannot use on SLR camera. And not as practical as Distagon. All in all Distagon structure provides SLR enthusiasts opportunity to explore wide angle world. As long as you don&amp;rsquo;t fear that big and heavy lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://lens-db.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/12/5d773dba6cf6c-1160x1160.jpg" width="40%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasselblad 903 SWC&lt;sup id="fnref:5"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to this &lt;strong&gt;Hasselblad CB 60mm f3.5&lt;/strong&gt; lens I own. Like most Distagon lenses. This is not a very light lens. Compared to Planar structure 80mm f2.8. Length longer bit. Weight also heavier bit. 60mm focal length equivalent conversion to 135 format about 35mm lens picture. Is an out-and-out small wide angle. Know played Leica know Leica players love 35mm lens. Like Seven Elements, Eight Elements existence like best quality in Leica world. Part comes from 35mm small wide angle characteristic can approach character and record character and surrounding scenery together. Has quite good realistic utility. This kind of lens also naturally positioned as humanity lens. And after actual use this 60mm lens for Hasselblad also indeed feel used to shoot humanity will be better than shooting landscape. And this slightly different from using Hasselblad for landscape photography most people think in heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;60mm this focal length not only appears in CB series. From earliest C series lenses to later CF, CFi series can see figure of 60mm f3.5. Except appearance change generation by generation. Optical design inside consistent. And 60mm f3.5 and 100mm f3.5 praised as two sharpest lenses in Hasselblad. Although CB series lens always considered cheap substitute of CF series. Also indeed in shutter function lacks F shutter used for Hasselblad 200F series. But on Hasselblad 500 series usage experience of this lens completely same as CF series. Even optical coating might be more advanced than CF series. Therefore this is still a very great choice under insufficient budget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sample-shots"&gt;Sample Shots
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Said so much lets see actual shooting appearance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First come a Freedom Square gate shot using &lt;strong&gt;Fujifilm Pro400h&lt;/strong&gt;. Can see still very slight wide angle distortion. And Zeiss optical aesthetic consistent high sharpness and high contrast. Can note rear National Concert Hall red pillars highlighted.
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/dTOSWuD.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look performance using &lt;strong&gt;Fujifilm Provia100f&lt;/strong&gt; positive film again:
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rdgmasm.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/yfrFRud.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Evening sky glowing with aesthetic purple. 60mm small wide angle just enough to collect whole Taipei Main Station McDonald&amp;rsquo;s
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/L2gOAZD.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
HK style roast meat shop hanging items. Texture clear after medium focus
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rZYzLlW.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Scene in traditional market. Brightness of vegetables fruits and characters of sign highlight feature of Zeiss lens. Especially colors of vegetables fruits restored very well. Have to say this lens very suitable for shooting such scene. Medium format own spatial sense plus 60mm small wide angle makes people feel immersed in it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Hasselblad of course still want be a landscape photographer. Look Pescadores scenery shot with &lt;strong&gt;Fujifilm Pro400h&lt;/strong&gt; below
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/XeHq8xJ.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Mediocre Penghu Great Bridge
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/NhC6xtk.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Building on a certain beach on Qimei Island. 60mm lens can blend foreground and background together very well
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/A71OaIA.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Interesting orange stone pier and blue green sea set off each other. When 60mm lens place horizon in center foreground ground proportion larger
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rUCflx1.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
This more like lens test. Can see slight distortion at edge
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/0NZlkNG.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Through blending chaos stones foreground and building background. More highlight desolation on island
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/iz9yg65.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/jlvBPMx.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Wide angle lens hard to highlight distant windmill. Sky proportion become too much
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/n9mWC9V.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally come two B&amp;amp;W photos under low light. Shot with &lt;strong&gt;ILFORD FP4&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/liBy0pn.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/aSOGEp4.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Make me more determined this is humanity lens no doubt&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choosing a lens needs consider its application scene. This is also why I love and hate this &lt;strong&gt;CB 60mm f3.5&lt;/strong&gt;. Love it because 35mm is my beloved focal length. I very like humanity, street theme photography. Pity it is a Hasselblad lens. Hasselblad&amp;rsquo;s big and clumsy body destined it is a very time-consuming operation camera. Suitable for slow rhythm photography. And for rapid change of street. I feel Hasselblad hard to adapt. Hasselblad destined to be camera born for landscape, for commercial photography. In such scene small wide angle lens appears not up not down. Not shocking as those ultra wide angle lens picture. Also not able focus on scenery in small range as telephoto lens. Or maybe for me Hasselblad with telephoto lens will be choice more suitable for me. So transferred this lens end of 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record this lens once owned with this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/uJL9pct.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.kenrockwell.com/leica/21mm-f4.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.kenrockwell.com/leica/21mm-f4.htm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://www.getit01.com/p20171220131505/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.getit01.com/p20171220131505/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:3"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://photographylife.com/lenses/leica-apo-telyt-m-135mm-f3-4-asph" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://photographylife.com/lenses/leica-apo-telyt-m-135mm-f3-4-asph&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:4"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.hasselbladhistorical.eu/HW/HWLds.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;http://www.hasselbladhistorical.eu/HW/HWLds.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:5"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://lens-db.com/camera/hasselblad-swc-with-carl-zeiss-biogon-t-38mm-f45-c-1959/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://lens-db.com/camera/hasselblad-swc-with-carl-zeiss-biogon-t-38mm-f45-c-1959/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink"&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mechanical Camera Series - Hasselblad A12 Magazine Loading Method</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/en/p/mechanical-camera-series-hasselblad-a12-magazine-loading-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 17:10:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/en/p/mechanical-camera-series-hasselblad-a12-magazine-loading-method/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/e1gynu4.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Mechanical Camera Series - Hasselblad A12 Magazine Loading Method" /&gt;&lt;h1 id="mechanical-camera-series---hasselblad-a12-magazine-loading-method"&gt;Mechanical Camera Series - Hasselblad A12 Magazine Loading Method
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2 id="preface"&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A while ago, I was pushed into the pit by a friend and bought a Hasselblad 500cm + CB 60mm 3.5f. As a medium format film SLR camera, the exquisiteness of its mechanical structure goes without saying. Even if not taking it out, playing with it in hands is still very enjoyable. Looking through the viewfinder, the optical beauty of Zeiss is revealed completely. The only drawback is that the huge body and weight are really inconvenient to take out. Bought it for a while but it has been kept in the dry box by me. Recently, I finally made up my mind to use it to take good photos. On a whim, I recorded how to use the Hasselblad A12 magazine to change film. For a novice using Hasselblad photography for the first time, I was surprised to find that there are many details to pay attention to. It is completely unlike 135 film cameras which are brainless. One careless mistake may destroy a roll of film and 12 hard-earned photographic works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/mYSbGqS.jpg" width="100%"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A black painted Hasselblad 500cm collected from an old master. Most people's impression of Hasselblad is the silver stainless steel outer edge, which has the beauty of classical crafts. The all-black Hasselblad has a modern feel and is more low-key. CB 60mm 3.5f was purchased from Pinkuan Photography. Originally wanted to match a mediocre 80mm, but the price of 80mm on the market was too scary at that time. CB 60mm is a high CP value choice. Sharpness and distortion are perfect. The viewing angle is also close to the 35mm lens of 135 format, but the actual shooting perspective is completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="start-loading-film"&gt;Start Loading Film
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id="remove-magazine"&gt;Remove Magazine
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/vC7wqpA.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/cTOmtCS.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing to do is remove the magazine from the body. Slide the round button on the magazine to the left side of the picture to unlock the latch and remove the magazine. &lt;strong&gt;Note that if the dark slide is not inserted back into the magazine, the latch cannot be moved.&lt;/strong&gt; Forcing it may cause mechanical damage. After removing the magazine, be careful not to touch the two door-like light shields behind the body, otherwise damaging them causing light leakage will not be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="pull-out-magazine-insert"&gt;Pull Out Magazine Insert
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/xDQEHyP.jpg" width="36%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/B0KDczd.jpg" width="64%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, take out the magazine insert inside. &lt;strong&gt;But before taking it out, be sure to check if there is still film inside.&lt;/strong&gt; If there is, confirm if it has finished rewinding. If you rashly take out the magazine insert, it will cause the film inside to be exposed to light, which would be miserable. Then just turn the knob on one side of the magazine from the left appearance to the right appearance and pull outward to pull out the magazine insert. Sometimes it may not be pulled out, &lt;em&gt;mostly because the dark slide is inserted backwards and stuck the magazine insert, so remember the dark slide also has directionality&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="exchange-spool"&gt;Exchange Spool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/iepOaK8.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/tY2pDPP.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extracted magazine insert looks like this. The one originally on the left is the old spool, which needs to be moved to the right. &lt;em&gt;So don&amp;rsquo;t lose the old spool&lt;/em&gt;. If lost, you can only go to &lt;del&gt;ask film developing shop for one&lt;/del&gt;. After Hasselblad magazine finishes shooting, it will rewind the film to the old spool, so every time the spool of the last film shot will be left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="film"&gt;Film
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/IZCVPns.jpg" width="18%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Ipbxo6M.jpg" width="18%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/bapytsW.jpg" width="32%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/NhSzGVp.jpg" width="32%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I am loading Kodak&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Portra 400&lt;/strong&gt; film. This roll should be one of the few satisfying films in the era of diminishing film types. Color latitude and detail are much better than the new Gold 200, and 400 ISO can provide relatively higher shutter speed. Except for the high price, it should be the first choice for 120 color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After opening the 120 film package, need to tear off the paper seal outside the film. The pulled out section is actually not film but backing paper, which is the biggest difference between 120 film and 135 film. Because 120 film has no shell, to prevent accidental exposure of film, need to rely on backing paper for light shielding. The real film is sandwiched in the middle of backing paper. Pulling to a certain position will pull out the real film together. The real film and backing paper are stuck together with a piece of paper tape. For detailed structure, can refer to this article: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.mobile01.com/topicdetail.php?f=255&amp;amp;t=495917" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;120 Film Structure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="install-film"&gt;Install Film
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/NLR08ER.jpg" width="64%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/3PapKLP.jpg" width="36%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First we install the film to the &lt;strong&gt;right side&lt;/strong&gt; where the spool was originally placed. Please note the &lt;strong&gt;direction&lt;/strong&gt; the backing paper is pulled out, it is pulled out from below. Do not install the film direction backwards. Then pull the backing paper to the back of the magazine insert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/cwIuRXY.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Z73oXiK.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wrapping the backing paper to the back, please note that there is a structure on the magazine insert for clamping the backing paper. This structure is clamped tight when the magazine insert is pulled out. We need to turn the knob of the magazine insert back to the original position first so that this backing paper clamping structure will loosen, making it convenient for the backing paper to pass from below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/7LBLhN5.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/47ezilB.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the backing paper passes, turn the knob of the magazine insert back to the open state, this structure will clamp the backing paper again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/HluUKiO.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/L7Ti5uu.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pass the end of the backing paper through the hole in the center of the old spool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/kkZv7mF.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/uCWNv1c.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we rotate the knob below the spool on the other side to tighten the backing paper. Continue rotating until the &lt;strong&gt;START arrow&lt;/strong&gt; (not necessarily have START) appears on the new film side. This arrow will align with the red arrow on the magazine. This completes the film installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="reinstall-magazine-insert"&gt;Reinstall Magazine Insert
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DQWH6WD.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Ayrb96e.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When reinstalling please note the position of the magazine insert knob. Need to tighten the backing paper clamping mechanism so the magazine insert can be installed into the magazine. After installing, turn the knob back to original position to complete magazine insert installation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rj4iVee.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/rMNGTb7.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hasselblad magazine needs to pre-roll film to the last frame. Can be understood as Hasselblad magazine starts shooting from the last frame. Therefore need to rotate the crank on the other side of magazine &lt;strong&gt;until the number 1 appears in the small window at the bottom left of magazine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align="center"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/6AvUQsX.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DSGryUW.jpg" width="50%" alt="Image description" &gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally install the magazine back to the body and can start shooting. &lt;strong&gt;Remember to confirm the body is already cocked when installing back to body&lt;/strong&gt;, otherwise installing magazine then cocking will make film shoot one less frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/f3WEITW.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Remember to pull out magazine dark slide when shooting, otherwise shutter cannot be pressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/qQO5bVJ.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;
Picture looking through viewfinder, Zeiss optical imaging is really beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="sample-shots"&gt;Sample Shots
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attach some Portra 400 sample shots for reference, processed by Violet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="new-google-building-under-construction-in-far-eastern-software-park"&gt;New Google Building under construction in Far Eastern Software Park
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/EadfVtx.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="logo-at-google-banqiao-office-entrance"&gt;Logo at Google Banqiao Office Entrance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/e1gynu4.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="google-banqiao-building"&gt;Google Banqiao Building
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/c5as5mB.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="second-floor-restaurant-downstairs-of-google-office"&gt;Second Floor Restaurant downstairs of Google Office
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/0FZUu7n.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="small-road-from-neihu-to-yehliu"&gt;Small road from Neihu to Yehliu
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/Wpy1WVq.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id="view-from-fengguizui"&gt;View from Fengguizui
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/BZ8hN1n.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="some-tips-for-a12-magazine"&gt;Some Tips for A12 Magazine
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="https://blog.huiminchi.com/%E5%93%88%E8%98%87hasselblad-a12-%E7%89%87%E5%A4%BE%E6%8B%8D%E6%94%9D%E7%AC%AC13%E5%BC%B5/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;A12 Magazine Stealing 13 Frames&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="link" href="http://www.photosharp.com.tw/FORUM/ArticleList.aspx?ForumId=4&amp;amp;TopicId=114634" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Magazine Serial Number Inconsistent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>