<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on 施星宇</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/page/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on 施星宇</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-tw</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>關於</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/%E9%97%9C%E6%96%BC/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="about-me"&gt;About Me
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is Hsing-Yu Shih (施星宇). I am currently working as a Firmware Engineer at Microsoft. I earned my master&amp;rsquo;s degree in EECS from National Taiwan University, where my area of specialization was Communication Engineering. My undergraduate studies were also completed at National Taiwan University, where I received a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in information management with a double major in forestry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My passion is magic, and during my college years, I held the position of vice president in the magic club and was an active performer. My involvement in the club provided me the opportunity to learn prop-making techniques, and I have gained a wealth of experience as a Maker through my participation in the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/DJdZN6N.jpg"
loading="lazy"
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my graduate studies, my research topic was the detection of suspicious accounts in online services, with a primary focus on data science, machine learning, and communication networks. Alongside my academic pursuits, I also participated in a photography club where I acquired knowledge of darkroom techniques and honed my photography skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2021, I had the opportunity to intern at Microsoft, which allowed me to gain a better understanding of the development technology and work model of a technology giant. As I anticipate graduating in the summer of 2022, I began my job search journey. After a thorough process, I am excited to have returned to Microsoft and to begin my career as a Software Program Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="about-this-site"&gt;About This Site
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2022, a friend reminded me that we had accumulated so much knowledge and experience that it was time to document it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="references"&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Framework Power by &lt;a class="link" href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme designed by &lt;a class="link" href="https://github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;hugo-theme-stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>典藏</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/archives/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>搜尋</title><link>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/search/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.hugoshih.com/zh-tw/search/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>